THE SUB-MAN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
理查德 能帮我查一下韦斯达的股价吗
Richard, can you get me the price of the Waystar stock?
-昨晚休市前的价格  -他怎么样了
- At close last night, please. - How is he?
不错 清醒点了 他还试着穿袜子
Good. A little clearer. He tried to put on a sock.
早
Hey.
Morning.
早啊 蒙代尔 祝我好运吧伙计
Hey, Mondale. Wish me luck, buddy.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
你说什么 "祝你好运 汤姆
What's that? "Good luck, Tom!
愿你一切顺利" 好吧
Hope it goes well!" OK, so,
我就想告个别
just wanted to say goodbye.
你看到价格了吗
Have you seen the numbers?
老天 可怜的肯 他让股价跟痢疾似的一泻千里
Man, poor Ken. He's like dysentery for the stock price.
你这可是跳火坑啊
You are walking into a burning barn.
还兴奋着呢
Still excited.
-跃跃欲试  -好吧
- Still rarin' to go. - Mm-hmm.
我只是来表表衷心
I'm just paying homage.
你说什么
What's that?
想我了吗 我也想你啊
You miss me? Well, I miss you too.
或许她不在的时候咱们应该约起来
Maybe we should arrange a date while she's not around.
-你个怪人  -不 你才怪人 好吧
- You're weird. - No, you are weird! OK!
-再见  -汤姆
- Goodbye. - Oh, Tom.
我要去看看爸
I'm gonna go see Dad.
如果玛西娅想来硬的 我也可以
If Marcia wants to be difficult, so can I.
你能和我一起吗
So...can you come with me?
我还是专心搞好这摊事吧 宝贝
Uh, I gotta stay in front on this one, baby.
是一摊大事
It's a hugie.
我的首次上位
My first morning stepping up.
就说你想去看望大佬呗
Just say you went to see the big boss.
-别逼我做选择 小西  -来吧
- Don't make me choose, Shiv. - Come on.
求你 别逼我做选择
Please. Don't make me choose.
不做选择是人的权利
It's a man's right not to choose.
拉瓦 给我半分钟好吗
Hey, Rava. Can you give me 30 seconds?
不好意思 我在帮孩子们做准备
Sorry, I'm just getting the kids ready.
露安 你能拿一下...
Oh, Luanne, can you get...
可以吗 好了
Yeah? OK.
-你好  -你好
- Hey. - Hi.
那什么...
Uh, yeah, so...
这事... 特别傻 但是今早银行来了电话
this is... this is dumb, but bank call this morning,
我就是想问...
and I just wanted to ask...
等下 什么银行 咱俩以前的联名账户吗
Wait. What bank? Our old joint account?
不是 拉瓦 那家银行
Um, no, no, Rava, the bank.
工商银行 一直给老爷子提供资金的那家
ICBC, who have apparently bankrolled the old man for years.
不好意思 我赶时间 好的
I'm sorry. I'm... just in a rush. OK.
就两分钟行吗
Just two minutes?
你怎么看
What's your read?
我是... 我是直接暴走[绿巨人] 还是温和点谈呢[布鲁斯·班纳]
Do I go... do I go Hulk, or Bruce Banner?
肯德尔 跟你公司的人谈去...
Well, K-Kendall, talk to your people about...
我知道 你就...
I know, you're just... you're
你一直很擅长这类东西  就...
always so good with this stuff, and just, uh...
绿巨人很无敌 对吧 绿巨人
The Hulk is the incredible one, right? The Hulk.
我得挂了 实在抱歉
We have to go. I'm sorry.
你去问罗曼吧 好吗
Why don't you ask Roman? OK?
-伙计们  -罗曼... 拉瓦 别这样
- Guys? - Roma... Rava. Come on.
-真的吗  -我很抱歉
- Seriously? - I'm sorry.
再见
Bye!
再见 孩子们 给你们比心
Bye, guys. Bye-bye. I love you.
翻译: 奶啾
翻译: 我的后面是猪精
翻译: 李木木
翻译: 这个家伙
翻译: Graaace
翻译: QueenBear
翻译: 海顿
翻译: 豆
时间轴: Heiforn
时间轴: 阿布
特效: 雨人
后期&压制: Jason肖
校对:渡渡
校对：宇宙万宝路
继     承
第 一 季  第３集
"救生艇"
监制: 宇宙万宝路
-十成痛感 你有几成  -七成
- Out of ten? - Uh, seven.
好的
Ok.
你的体态很好
You're in decent shape,
皮肉稍微有点松 但我能把你练得像鼓面一样紧绷
you're a little sloppy, but I can get you tight as a drum.
我相信帕克斯 帕克斯说你无人能及
Ah. Well, I trust Pax, and Pax says you're the best.
我就说一件事 罗曼
I'm only gonna say one thing, Roman, OK?
说吧
Go for it.
我对待工作相当认真
I take my shit serious,
所以我在圈子里名声这么好
that's why I have the reputation that I do,
我需要你也认真对待这事 好吗
and I need you to take it serious, too. OK?
大哥 我... 我来都来了
Dude, I'm... I'm onboard,
你就省省口舌吧
so you can skip the whole speech bullshit, OK?
-我肯定认真  -好的 每天五点半过来
- I'm down. - All right. 5:30 every day.
大哥 我很严肃啊 比癌症还严肃[重]
Yeah, man, I'm serious. I'm serious as cancer.
比那更严肃 操他娘的孔方兄之癌
Fuckin' more serious. Fuckin' money cancer.
我现在是COO了
You know, I'm COO now.
-是吗  -是啊
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah.
就是首席运营官
That's Chief Operating Officer.
在韦斯达·罗伊科公司 公司运营事项我说了算
It's Waystar Royco, so if it operates, I chief it.
翻个身
Flip over on your belly.
好
Yeah. Ahh.
但是 好吧 五点半 很好
But yeah, no, 5:30, that's perfect.
-早上 是吗  -是
- A.M. Right? - Yup.
那就好 因为下午五点半的时候我在工作呢 你知道不
Well, good, because the other 5:30 I'll be at work, ya know?
作为变革推动者搞事情 解雇职员什么的
Being an agent of change and fuckin' firing people.
谢谢
Thank you.
让她在那儿等着
Ask her to wait there.
她在这儿呢
Oh! She's here.
是吗啡的错
It's the morphine.
-司空见惯了  -我知道 我还好
- It's not that unusual. - I know. I'm fine.
-没什么事吧  -你好 小西
- Is everything all right? - Hi, Shiv.
-你好  -你好 汤姆
- Hi! - Hi, Tom.
恐怕我不能久留
Hey. I'm afraid I can't stay.
-恕我失陪  -第一天
- Excuse me one second. - First day.
-你好  -出什么...
- Hi. - What's the...
出什么事了
What's going on?
-没事  -没有吗
- Nothing. - No?
员工情绪
Staff.
见到你很高兴
Good to see you.
我知道你说过他状态不是很好
Yeah. I know you said that he wasn't great,
但是我路过这边
but I was passing by,
就想顺便拜访一下
so I thought I'd just drop in.
你太贴心了
That is so sweet.
但是他现在还不想见人
But you know, he's not seeing people right now.
我知道 但我就想露个面
Yeah, but I thought I could just pop up.
就算他发飙也没事
Even if, you know, he's grumpy.
我觉得你最好不要
I think it's best you don't.
玛西娅 我见过老爸断食的样子
Marcia, I've seen my dad do the Master Cleanse.
应该能顶得住他的怒火
I can take him a little bit grouchy.
我觉得这事没得商量
I'm afraid that is out of the question.
你... 能不能
Um, do you... Might it be an idea
去问问他是否转变了心意呢
to check and see whether he's changed his mind?
-是啊  -精神稍微振作了点呢
- Yeah. - Perked up a little bit?
当然
Of course.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
谁说不是呢 我得走了
I know. I have to go.
好 我知道
Yeah, I know.
你好啊 你好
Oh, hey. Hello. Hi!
我是小西
I'm Shiv.
洛根的女儿
Logan's daughter.
我只是... 想说句谢谢...
I just... I wanted to say thank you for...
谢谢你做的一切
for all your work.
你太客气了
You're quite welcome.
-我们很感激  -谢谢
- Yeah. It's much appreciated.  - Thank you.
他今天怎么样了
And how does he seem today?
还好吗
Good?
就那样... 你懂的
Oh... you know.
事实上 我们不大懂
Actually, we don't.
我们听说了袜子的事
We heard all about the sock.
对
Yeah.
最后成交价
股价会稳定下来的
It'll stabilize.
我知道 一定会的
I know. I know it will.
那个... 我一直在想
So... I've been thinking.
我针对这通电话制定了新的战术
I've got a new game plan for the call.
然后呢
Uh-huh.
你能试着别摆出一副紧张死了的样子吗
Can you try and not look so fuckin' nervous?
我清楚自己在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
我不紧张
I'm relaxed.
只是考虑到事态的严重性 和改善关系的需要
I just think it's a little late, considering the gravity
这个改动怕是有些迟
and the need to get the relationship right.
当然 新的... 新策略只是针对我们现阶段成果的
Sure. The... The new strategy is really just a refinement
一些精炼和细化
of all this great work.
它主要是...
It goes, uh...
怎么说呢 策略名称暂定为"去你妈的"
Well, the working title is "Go Fuck Yourself."
好吧
Uh-huh.
您好 波尔克先生来电
Hi, I have Mr. Polk.
好吧 你觉得怎么样
Uh-huh. What do you think?
我觉得你得再跟我解释一下
I think I need a little bit more of an explanation.
我爸是个混球 得让他们明白我也不是善茬
My dad's a bastard, they need to know I'm a bastard, too.
-对吗  -对...
- Right?  - Right...
很好
Great.
您好 波尔克先生
Hey, Mr. Polk.
你好 肯德尔 很高兴跟你通话
Hi, Kendall, good to connect.
我也是 没错 是很好
Likewise. Yeah, great.
那么 你... 想先说吗
So, you... you wanna go?
不如你先说吧
Well, why don't you go?
好吧 当然了
OK. Well, uh, sure.
鉴于当前的处境 我们想与贵司保持联系
We just wanted to make contact, given where we are.
-理解 我们考虑到了  -当然
- Mm-hmm. We are concerned.  - Absolutely.
很显然 现在最主要的事情是
Now, obviously, look, the main thing is,
我们要处理得十分镇定
we just handle this very calmly,
毕竟咱们双方都不想
because the last thing either of us want
让我父亲的私下安排
is for this rather private arrangement my father made
掀起不必要的风浪
to, uh, you know, make waves.
-当然了  -但问题在于
- Absolutely.  - But I guess the issue is
我们欠你32亿...
we owe you 3.2 billion...
32.5亿
3.25.
我只是四舍五入一下
Hey, I was rounding down.
那怎么不算33亿
We round up.
32.5亿
3.25 billion,
作为对于韦斯达股价的担保
secured against Waystar stock,
而这支股票 由于一些全行业的普遍因素
which is, you know, undergoing some temporary turbulence
正在经历一些短暂的起伏
due to sector-wide factors.
没错
Mm-hmm.
所以 我觉得
So, I guess, you know,
我想知道的是
what I'd like to know is,
如果我们的股价持续下跌
what your position will be
然后单方面解除债务契约的话
if we have a sustained breach of the stock price
你们将采取什么立场
and we fall out of compliance with our debt covenant?
这么说吧 如果股价继续下跌
OK, well, if the stock drops,
我们有权要求全额赔偿
we're entitled to ask for a payment in full.
没错
Uh-huh, exactly.
原则上讲得通
Technically, uh, yeah.
那么... 在现实中该怎么做呢
So... what will we do here in reality?
如果股价跌下130美元 你们就违约了
If it breaches 130, you've broken the covenant
需要赔付我们的损失
and we will want repayment.
没错
Right.
我清楚
I know.
但是 真的要赔吗
But, um, like, really?
真的
Seriously.
好 我... 我懂了
OK, I... I get it.
这是你们最初的立场
That's your initial position,
但我们想要做些调整
but we will want to restructure,
还有...
and, uh...
听着 我是这么想的
Look, here's where I'm at.
我们不想要传媒部
We're not crazy about the media sector,
也不在乎你父亲怎么对待我们的关系
we're not crazy about how your father has treated our relationship,
我们的立场是拿到赔偿
and our position is to seek recoupment.
得了吧 哥们 滚球吧你
Oh, come on, man. Fuck off.
-还在听吗  -在
- Uh, hello?  - I'm here.
好的 好 直说吧
Yeah. Yeah, come on.
现实一点 我们能好好谈判吗
Real world, can we start to negotiate?
听着 小子 我已经讲过了
Listen, son, that's our position.
如果股价跌下130美元
If the stock drops below 130,
你们违约 我们就把钱要回来
you're in breach and we want our money back.
好吧 行 继续谈
OK, fine. Let's keep talking.
听着 如果你想跟我谈
Look, if you need to talk to me,
最好找个人传话
maybe it's better if we go through an intermediary.
我不喜欢爆粗口
I'm not a particular fan of foul language,
也不喜欢被冒犯
and I don't like to be insulted.
谢谢 祝你早安
Thank you, good morning.
倒大霉了
Oh, boy.
-操 太惨了  -你刚刚在偷听吗
- Fuck, that was brutal.  - You were listening in?
当然了 我可是首席运营官
Of course I was in. I'm COO.
他们... 他们认真的吗 真的会勒索我们吗
Are... Are they for real?  Would they squeeze us?
-他们显然可以这么做  -是的 但他们图什么
- Well, obviously they could.  - Yeah, but why would they?
冷静点 哥 都会好起来的
Relax, man, it'll be fine.
不会的 好个锤子 行吗
Uh, no, it fuckin' necessarily won't. OK?
如果这事儿公开了
If this became public,
股价暴跌 我们就死透了
we could nosedive, we could death spiral here.
哥们 我只是安慰你一下
Dude, I was only trying to be nice.
真他妈的一出滑稽秀
That was a fucking shitshow,
你表现得像个弱智一样 这才是实话
and you handled it like a moron, is the truth.
滚一边去
Fuck off.
先生们
Gents.
你好 我是格雷格·赫施
Hello. Uh, Greg Hirsch.
从今天起在这里上班
I believe I'm working here as of today.
好的 你的职位名称是什么
OK, what is your job or job title?
职位的话 我不是很确定
Um, job, not entirely sure, per se.
我会查出来的
I'll find out.
是这样的 我们这里没有任何记录
OK, um, I don't have anything.
我实际上是洛根·罗伊先生亲自聘用的
I was actually personally appointed by Mr. Logan Roy.
好吧 这...
OK. Um...
-这...  -还有谁能证明呢
- Um... - Is there anyone else, maybe?
汤姆
Tom?
-汤姆  -姓什么
- Tom.  - Last name?
姓什么...
Last name, uh...
奇怪了 我好像从来不知道他姓什么...
Weird, I don't think I ever got his last...
就是... 那个老板 汤姆
Uh, T... boss Tom...
汤姆 汤姆
Tom? Tom?
-你好 这里  -你好
- Hey! Hey!  - Hey.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
能帮我...
Can you help...
好吧 格雷格 格雷格·罗伊吗
OK, Greg. Greg Roy?
应该是... 我姓赫施
That's the... I'm actually a Hirsch.
我不是... 我妈妈姓罗伊 但是
I'm not a... My mom's a Roy, but, uh,
我算是罗伊家的人... 除了名字
I'm basically a Roy in all... all but my name.
-等等  -给我两分钟
- Wait...  - I'll be two minutes.
怎么回事 别 别 小西...
What? No. No. Shiv...
事情的走向很古怪 非常古怪
It has gotten weird. OK? It has gotten very weird.
-他怎么样了  -不清楚
- How is he?  - I don't know.
-好像能穿袜子了  -那挺好的 不是吗
- He might have put on a sock.  - Well, that's good, right?
也说不定死在床上了 我他妈不知道
Or he could be lying there dead. I have no fuckin' idea.
好吧 那个...
OK, this is...
不是说这个的时候
It's not a good time.
她觉得玛西娅在给老爸下毒
She thinks that Marcia's poisoning him.
我没有 很明显他不想见我们
I do not. Apparently, he doesn't want to see us.
不包括我呦
Not including me?
他干嘛那么说
Why would he say that?
还在生你的气呗
Still pissed at you
谁让你不签署公司重组的文件呢
for not signing up to his corporate restructure
不给玛西娅成为女王的机会
to make Marcia queen of the castle?
好吧 那就是她在生气
OK, yeah. Maybe she's pissed.
你们周末去看他了吗
Look, did you see him over the weekend?
没 我听说他还不能见人
No. I heard he wasn't up to seeing people.
是啊 自从那天把他从医院带回家
Yeah, no one has seen him
就没人见过他
since we took him home from the hospital,
貌似是 周四
like, Thursday.
我猜... 小罗见过他 对吗
I think... Rome? You saw him, right?
没错 大概五分钟吧
Uh, sure, yeah, for, like, five minutes.
但他... 有点...
But he was, um... he was pretty...
不像他的状态 身上全是管子和...
He wasn't really him him, there were tubes and...
-那次之后呢  -没见过
- OK, but after that?  - Nope.
除了玛西娅没人见过他
No one apart from Marcia has seen him
都快一周了
for the better part of a week.
-四天可不是一周  -行 那就一周的大部分
- Four days is not a week.  - OK, the majority of the week,
我们只是听...
and we're just accepting...
全世界都只是听这个女人说
the whole world is just accepting this woman's word
老爸能他妈穿袜子了
that he put on a fucking sock.
放松点 好吗
Look, relax, OK?
这需要过程
I-It's a process,
我们不想他恢复得仓促...
we don't want to rush the recovery...
没错 因为你喜欢当老板对吗
Oh, right, because you like playing boss?
不是...
That's not...
求你了 能去那边一趟吗
Please. Can you go over there?
小西 是这样...
Shiv, this is...
我确实有些事必须处理
I literally have something unmissable.
晚些 好吗 我尽力
Later. OK? I'll try later.
-好吗  -好
- Ok?  - ok.
一切还好吗
Is everything OK?
不好 公司怕是要垮了
No. We are on the brink of total corporate collapse.
对 意料之中
Oh, yeah. Well, that figures.
雷曼事件: 美国第四大投资银行雷曼兄弟申请破产
引发全球金融海啸
破产了记得打给我 好吗
Well, call me if you go Lehman, will you?
可能需要这里几把椅子
Might want some of these chairs.
早上好
Morning.
来帮忙修复死星[星战帝国战斗空间站]了
Here to help fix the Death Star.
"大伙 人为刀俎
"Grill on the exhaust vent, guys,
我为鱼肉啊"
grill on the exhaust vent."
我唯一担心的是 缩短会议时间
So, my only concern would be, to brief this meeting,
代理总裁这么做会不会有点强势了
is it a little too aggressive for a temporary CEO?
我也这么认为
That is a good point.
咱们的股价都跌成那样了
Yeah, well, we've got a very aggressive drop
我不觉得有什么不合适
in our share price, so I think that's appropriate, good?
压缩好会议内容和时间 好吗
So brief this wide and brief it fast, OK?
-明白  -很好
- OK.  - Uh, yeah. Great.
好了 好了
All right, all right!
早上好啊
Morning, morning, morning.
我的同伴们
My people.
很高兴见到大家
It's great to see you all.
我和我弟弟 总裁和首席执行官...
You know my brother and I, CEO and COO...
-首席执行官  -还有格丽 卡尔 卡洛丽娜
- COO.  - Gerri, Karl, Karolina.
能行的话
I'm actually gonna stand up,
我就站着了
if that's all right.
我的背巨他妈疼 我换了个新教练 所以...
My back is fucked. I have a new trainer, so...
我想在任职期间早点把大家聚起来
So, I just wanted to get the gang together early in my tenure
跟你们说... "呦"
to say, uh... "Yo."
可能你们都想知道我父亲的情况
You're probably all wondering about my dad.
他很好
He's doing OK.
狗杂种
Motherfucker.
我们盼望他能痊愈
We're hoping for a full recovery.
虽然他的确好了很多
He's, like, a thousand percent better, though.
他可是坚不可摧啊[披犀牛皮的公牛]
He's like a bull in rhino hide.
没错 恢复得慢了点但很稳定
Uh-huh. Yeah. Slow and steady.
今早他自己穿的袜子 所以...
This morning he put on a sock, so...
是啊 今早他试着穿袜子...
That's right. Uh, this morning he tried to put on a sock.
大家欢迎汤姆·威姆士丹
And welcome to Tom Wamsgans,
他以前负责南部与中部的度假区
who was managing Resorts South and Central
现在要跟大人们平起平坐了
and is now sitting up with the grownups.
-我只是想...  -今天我想
- Hey. I just want... - So, what I want to announce
跟大家宣布新的战略构想
to you all this morning is a new strategic vision.
我们有一家伟大的公司
We have a great firm here.
经营面广泛
Multifaceted.
公园 巡游
Parks, cruises,
电信 生活娱乐 运动...
telecom, live entertainment, sports...
但核心是媒体
but at the heart, media.
电视 电影 书刊 报纸
TV, movies, books, newspapers.
我们要博人眼球
And what we're fighting for is eyeballs,
把那些观众转化成客户群
eyeballs which we convert to our customer base,
把他们打包卖给广告商
eyeballs which we crate up and sell to advertisers.
对吗 另外在底价上 我们输了...
Right? And bottom line, we're losing...
输给了打破垄断的公司
to monopolistic disruptors.
Alphabet: 谷歌重组后的"伞形公司"
Alphabet 脸书...
Alphabet, Facebook...
互联网 该死的逆转者
Internet. Fucking game-changer, man.
-是啊 互联网  -互联网
- That's right, the internet.  - Internet.
但我们还是可以... 有可能...
But, uh, we are still just... just... in a position
能带着我们的品牌进军新领域
to leverage our brands into something in the new landscape.
否则 我们他妈的就跟
But if we don't, we're gonna be like
二十世纪底特律的马贩子没有区别 懂吗
the biggest fuckin' horse trader in Detroit, 1909. OK?
我们需要更灵活的策略
We need a more dynamic strategy.
为清楚起见 就叫它
Now, let's call it, for the sake of clarity,
"救生艇战略"
the Strategy of a Thousand Lifeboats.
沃尔特公司就是一艘救生艇
Vaulter is a lifeboat,
泛美网络科技公司也是一艘救生艇
ATN Citizens is a lifeboat.
不存在坏的救生艇
There are no bad lifeboats.
虚拟实境能成为救生艇
VR could be a lifeboat.
虚拟实境是个气泡
VR's a bubble,
不过不算个坏主意
but yeah. No bad ideas.
色情片也能成为救生艇
Porn could be a lifeboat.
除了这个 这是艘坏船
Except that. That's a bad lifeboat.
谢了 小罗
Hey, thanks, Rome.
但这不是在玩头脑风暴
Look, this isn't a brainstorm,
我要说的是 每个人我都欢迎 好吗
all I'm saying, everyone's invited. OK?
我希望每个人都能
I want each and every one of you
有创造力 敢于挑战
to be innovating, challenging,
大胆地掀起这次风浪
being bold, being disruptive,
制作崭新的 有创意的多平台内容
bringing me new, original, multiplatform content.
发掘交互数字空间
Bring me more in the interactive and digital space.
引进特许知识产权
Bring me franchiseable IP.
带给我千万艘救生艇
Bring me a thousand lifeboats.
博取更多人的眼球
Bring me a fucking armada of eyeballs.
毕竟船开再稳都会撞上冰山
Because steady as she goes hits the iceberg.
好了 感谢大家
All right. Thanks, everyone.
救生艇
Lifeboats! Whoo!
不得不说 刚才的会开得太好了 赞
Just had to say, that was great. Kudos.
你想倾诉的话我一直在
Always here if you need a friendly ear,
维德大人[星战人物]
Lord Vader.
赶紧运营好公园
Just get shit moving at Parks.
-好  -好吗 汤姆
- Yes. - Yeah, Tom?
那就是一潭死水
It's stagnant,
就靠你搅活它了 C3PO[星战机器人]
so shake that fuckin' tree, C3PO.
我搅 我搅
Shakin' the tree. Shakin' the tree.
我搅搅搅
Shakin' it big time.
菲奥娜 跟我来
Fiona. Walk with me.
麻烦你送束花给拉瓦
Can you send flowers to Rava?
好看 但别太夸张的
Nice, but, you know, not ridiculous.
闻的是花香 而不是我的绝望感
They should smell like flowers, not desperation.
还有 和杰西谈谈
and Fi, talk to Jess,
我可能会先在公司里搞点事
I might want to throw a couple of items up on the internal.
不是什么大事 就几个TED演讲
Not a big deal, couple of TED talks.
我在考虑 也许放个"吉尔伽美什史诗"纪录片
Maybe a documentary on the Epic of Gilgamesh, I'm thinking?
因为这是第一个故事 探索的始祖
You know, it's the first story, archetypal quest shit.
而我们不讲故事还能干什么
Because what are we if not storytellers?
现在怎么样了
Hey. Talk to me.
降了三个点
Down three points,
还有美联社的头条
and there's an AP headline
"总裁向员工承认韦斯达正驶向冰山"
"CEO tells staff Waystar headed for iceberg."
谁说冰山了 救生艇 我说的救生艇
Not iceberg, lifeboats. I said lifeboats, not iceberg!
-老天 卡洛丽娜  -我们就是这么解释的
- Jesus! Karolina. - That's what we're pushing.
-加把劲  -我保证
- Push harder. - Will do.
我想和你谈几个可行性 好吗
I want to talk options to you, OK?
我一直在酝酿几个主意...
I've got some thoughts I've been working on for a long time...
够了 我不想听老生常谈
OK, I don't want the sloppy seconds,
格丽 我先休息下想大事
Gerri. I'm taking five to think big.
肯 这些都是通过建模 思考周详的...
Ken, these are modeled and thought through...
同时也被拒的
And rejected.
现在 恕我失陪 我要去走走
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm talking a walk,
我得去找点高见
I need to get some altitude on this.
一会回来
I'll be back.
资本主义的关键在于
The thing about capitalism is, yeah, sure,
它是有一些问题 但妈的...
it's got its issues, but fuck me...
这是一条没有伸展性的屎链
this is a piece of shit chain on a stretch of nothing,
但这个... 这是
but this... this is the most
人类史上最好吃的东西
delicious thing anyone's ever fucking tasted.
老天爷 太好吃了
Oh, my God. Thank you.
-谢谢  -兄弟 听着
- Thank you. - So dude, listen.
-怎么  -我想听听
- Mm-hmm? - I could do with a read
一个局外人的看法
from someone without a dog in the fight.
其实 我也有话要和你说
Actually, I gotta talk to you about something, too.
这是机密
This is tight.
绝对不能泄露给第三个人 好吗
This is absolutely just us, OK?
一旦泄露我就完了
Because a leak kills me.
好的 其实是拉瓦
Right. This is about Rava.
-为了一位朋友  -拉瓦
- For a pal. - Rava?
对 一位共同朋友
Yeah, it's a mutual friend,
他们想知道一切都在掌握中
and they want to know is it cool,
还是你仍想当个瘪三
or you still hankerin' for a wankerin'?
我没时间猜了
I don't have time for this.
我想知道... 到底谁在问
I mean, who... who's asking?
-啥玩意  -我不能细说
- What? - I can't say.
但他们只想知道这是不是个大问题
But they just want to know if it's an issue.
到底谁 傻逼保罗吗
Like who, fuckin' Paul?
既然你还在问 那我猜确实有大问题
Well, if you're asking, I'm assuming it's a fucking issue.
没有 我们分居了 你懂吗
No, I mean, look, we're separated, you know?
别紧张 自由代理
Whatever. Free agents.
好 我懂
Yeah. No, I get it.
我还要再吃一个
I'm gonna have another.
知道吗 如果你吃得够快
You know, if you eat it fast enough
还能帮助燃烧卡路里
it actually burns off the calories.
就像个漏洞
It's like a loophole.
请给我再来一个
Can I have another, please?
听着 我接手后...
So, listen, when I took over...
发现我父亲 在二十年前
found out Dad took out a huge loan
偷偷地通过控股公司贷款了一大笔钱
a decade ago. Secret. Through the holding company.
真的吗
Are you serious?
拿家族在公有企业的股份做的抵押
Secured against the family's stake in the public firm.
真操蛋 哥们
Fuck. Dude.
是啊 现在股票就要触底了
Yeah. Now the stock is getting ready to breach,
-银行那边也...  -我知道 我看了今天的股价
- and the bank are... - Yeah, I know, I saw the price.
很血腥 哪家银行
It's brutal. Who's the bank?
我要这么干
Mm-hmm. I'm just gonna do this.
老兄...
Dude...
我们已经不在巴克莱了 天呐
we're not at Buckley anymore. Jesus.
没事的
It's fine.
所以 这群人掌握着你的小弟弟
So, these guys have your dick in a vise.
是的 "谢谢" 斯图伊
Yes. Thank you, Stewy.
你能说说看法吗
Can I have your take?
首先 你提高股价
Well, number one, you boost the price.
-我怎么没想到 夏洛克大侦探  -好吧
- Yeah, no shit, Sherlock. - OK.
-我在努力  -好吧
- I'm trying. - OK.
我们怎么做才能拿到再融资
How's it gonna play for us to refinance?
说真的吗 不乐观
Honestly? Not great.
原来的投资银行怎么不凑上来 不看好
Why won't your original bank step up? Not good.
大家不喜欢这个行业
People don't love the sector,
更不喜欢这个玩蛋的公司
and they don't love the fucking firm.
大家都看衰
It's ramshackle, is the view.
还有 兄弟 他们也不... 喜欢你
And bro, they don't love... you.
情况很糟
It's tough.
操了
Ah, fuck it.
好了 我开始营业了
OK! I am open for business.
我想到一件事
You know, one thing occurs.
只是随便说说 也不一定会成真
Just blue sky, wouldn't happen in a million years,
但如果
but what if
我们插手
we came in,
从你们家族手里把公司接过来呢
took the whole thing off your family's hands?
好吧 绝对不行
Uh, well, obviously no,
玩蛋去 你好大胆子 我被冒犯了 之类的回答
fuck off, how dare you, I'm so insulted, et cetera.
当然了 但你和罗曼 小西
Of course. But you and Roman and Shiv,
你们打算一辈子做这个事 当然不会
you're gonna do that thing forever? No.
你们能有机会变得他妈的...
You all have the chance to be fucking...
和石油大亨一样有钱
fucking, like, ugly petro-ruble rich.
你们能做任何事
You can do anything.
你可以进科技产业
You can go into tech,
小西可以搞她的政治 或者别的什么
Shiv can do her politics or whatever,
罗曼可以 你懂的 继续嗑药减肥
and Roman can, you know, snort his body weight.
然后大家一起过着痛苦的一生
And you all live unhappily ever after.
是哦 多谢 斯图伊
Uh-huh. Thanks, Stewy.
考虑一下
Just think about it.
明天 我想召集所有的高层
Can I get the senior team together tomorrow
重订一次方向
for a reorientation?
搅活水 大伙 搅活了
Shakin' the tree, folks, shakin' the tree.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
格雷格 你开玩笑吧
Greg? Are you kidding?
你好啊 汤姆
Hey, Tom.
不好意思 但...
Forgive me, but, uh...
我们是要在大帆船的便便甲板上说话吗
we talkin' to each other on the poop deck of a majestic schooner?
是咸咸的海水刺痛了我水手的皲脸吗
Is the salty brine stinging my weather-beaten face?
不是吧
No?
那你他妈为何穿帆布鞋来上班 哥们
Then why the fuck are you wearing a pair of deck shoes, man?
不是的 听我解释
No, well,
我的信用卡刷爆了 我住在青年旅舍
my credit card got maxed out, I'm staying in a youth hostel
-480块一天...  -老天 真脏
- on, like, $80 a day... - Jesus. How squalid.
哥们 你那是一袋狗屎吗
Dude, are you carrying dog shit?
不... 这是...
No... No, it's, uh...
饼干是免费的 对吗
it's free, right?
我能拿走吗
Is that cool? I mean,
我并不想夸张
I don't wanna be melodramatic,
但我的身体因为缺少营养越来越虚了
but my body is growing weak due to a lack of sustenance.
非要放狗屎袋里吗
But in a dog poop baggie?
我从家里带了很多过来...
Yeah, I have a bunch of 'em from back home...
太恶心了 格雷格
Greg, that's disgusting.
不会啊
Not really.
把屎装进去之前里面又没屎
It's not like they pre-poop them or something,
又不是... 就是袋子嘛
like, it's not like... they're just bags, really.
你心里过不去而已
It's just a mental barrier.
赶紧置办一双克罗基特琼斯的开普托牛津鞋
A pair of cap-toe Oxfords, Crockett & Jones, ASAP.
露辛达 能给多才多艺的格雷格先生找份活儿干吗
Lucinda, can we figure out where we might put the talented Mr. Greg?
-纳森尼尔  -西沃恩
- Nathaniel. - Siobhan.
最近怎么样
How have you been?
挺好的 有点忙
Uh, yeah, good. Busy.
这样
Right.
这算是...
So, is this...?
工作
Work.
-行 当然了  -对
- OK. Of course. - Yeah.
-怎... 怎么了  -工作
- Wh... What? - Work.
在四星级酒店的床上开个小工作会议
A little work meeting on the bed of a four-star hotel.
-想什么呢你  -好吧
- Get your mind out of the gutter. - Ok.
你和... 乔伊丝处得怎么样
How's it goin' workin' with... Joyce?
tall glass of water=辣妹 tepid反义
那个奥尔巴尼[纽约州首府]来的丑女
That tall glass of tepid water from Albany.
还不错 真的
It's great. Yeah.
卡斯特罗: "古巴国父" 古巴革命武装力量的主要缔造者 传被暗杀了638次
那可怜的菲德尔·卡斯特罗怎么样了
How's the, uh, poor man's Fidel Castro?
1975年就当上了资深参议员
Senior senator from the state of 1975.
你们处得如何
How's that workin' out for ya?
比以前好
Better. Zing!
能不能帮我个忙
I wondered if you could do me a favor.
我欠你人情吗
Do I owe you a favor?
欠呀 就凭我屈尊跟你谈过恋爱
Yeah, 'cause I deigned to date you.
你屈尊 "说得真好"
You deigned. That's nice.
我那时还以为咱们能做朋友
And I thought we were gonna be friends.
没错 当朋友挺好的
Sure. I wanna be friends.
我查一个人的背景
I need a background check on somebody.
这可能会引出道德问题
Well, that might cause some ethical issues.
因为眼下我的人和你的人
'Cause there's a world where my guy and your gal
为了民主党总统提名打得你死我活
end up in the mud wrestling for the Democratic nomination.
不 这和政治无关
No, it's not political.
我要暗地里查一个人的背景
I need background on someone off the record.
-是玛西娅  -玛西娅
- Uh, Marcia. - Marcia.
-邪恶后妈  -就是她
- The wicked stepmother. - Yeah.
过了这么多年我才发现
It occurred to me a few years too late
我对她一无所知
that I don't really know anything about her.
就当尽职调查[人员和资产的审核]
So... just due diligence.
好吗
OK?
我认识个狠角色
I know a really horrible guy
要价超高
who's incredibly expensive.
行 那就说定了
OK. Yeah, that sounds great. OK.
-你做中间人吗  -是的 夫人
- All goes through you? - Yes, milady.
好
Ok.
-"屈尊"  -是啊
- "Deigned." - Yeah.
你见过我后来谈的女人吗
Did you see the women I dated after you?
当然 她们选你完全是因为你跟我谈过
Yeah. They only dated you because you dated me.
她们心里肯定想 "这男人一定有点本事"
They were like, "Oh, I guess he must have something."
韦斯达多样性和骚扰政策
Waystar diversity and harassment policy.
韦斯达·罗伊科长久以来致力于维护包容
Waystar Royco has worked hard to develop a tolerant
且互相尊重的工作环境
and respectful workplace.
公司严格执行
The company is strongly committed
基于有效条件的
to making employment decisions
雇佣政策
based on valid requirements
该政策不因以下条件区别对待 如种族 宗教 国籍
and without regards to race, religion, national origin,
血统 性别 性别认同
ancestry, gender, gender identity,
性别用语 性别偏好
gender expression, sex preference,
性取向 生理和心理障碍
sexual orientation, physical or mental disability,
兵役状况 婚姻状况
military status, marital status,
或其他受现有法律保护的个人状况
or any other status as is protected by applicable law.
在法律规定的反歧视行动计划部分
Where the law requires affirmative action programs,
公司将努力确保该计划严格依法执行
the company will strive to comply with the provisions of those laws.
感谢您的收看
Thank you for your attention.
在韦斯达·罗伊科迎接你崭新的未来吧
Welcome to your new future at Waystar Royco.
用心感受
Feel it!
股价怎样了
Where we at?
我们又掉了两个百分点
We're down two more points.
桑迪·弗尼斯来了
Listen, Sandy Furness is here.
-什么意思  -他来了
- What do you mean? - I mean, he's here,
-进咱们公司了  -怎么可能
- in the building. - He can't do that.
百事又他妈不会去可口可乐串门
Fucking Pepsi doesn't just drop in to see Coke.
安排下别让其他人看到他
Put him where no one can see him.
南厢 我马上到
South tank. I'm right here.
危机四伏
Sharks are circling.
你爸见到他会一枪崩了他
Your father would shoot him on sight.
我不想听你说我爸现在会做什么
You know, I don't need to hear what my father would do right now.
-懂吗 他又不在  -好的
- OK? He's not here. - Right.
-我能处理  -他不在这儿
- I'm gonna handle it. - He's not here.
弗尼斯先生 真是意外
Mr. Furness, what a surprise.
-你能过来真是太好了  -客气了
- So kind of you to drop by. - Oh, not at all.
我来慰问一下 你爸现在这样真是太遗憾了
I just came to say how sorry I was to hear about your dad.
谢谢你亲自过来
Well, it's so kind of you to do it in person
其实打个电话就行了
when you could have just called.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我希望这次拜访看上去不是挑衅
Well, I hope I didn't send the birds a-tweeting,
毕竟不确定因素太多
what with all the uncertainty and whatnot.
我们会让外界知道这是友善的会面
We'll make sure people know it's just friendly.
代我向你爸问好 告诉他我来过
And you'll give your dad my best, tell him I stopped by?
当然 没问题
Of course. Sure.
要不等他... 能受得了刺激的时候再说吧
Maybe when that news is, uh... less likely to kill him.
那行 谢谢你 我非常感激
Okay, well, thank you. I do... I appreciate this.
就随便说一句
Oh, and just to say,
我能帮你出出主意
if, um, I can give you any advice,
反正现在老了没事干
I'm just watching the wheels nowadays,
要是需要我当诚实中间人[中立的调停角色]
so if you want to run anything by me
管理公司的话 就告诉我
as an honest broker, use me.
我可以当导师
A mentor.
谢谢你能这么说
That is a very kind offer.
我们两家公司之间有数不清的选择
Well, there's probably a million options with our two firms.
互换[利率 外汇 商品 股权等] 收购 协同合作
Swaps, acquisitions, cooperative interactions.
聪明人的游戏
You know, smart stuff
只有你们年轻人能够想象
only a young man like you can conceive of.
桑迪
Well, Sandy,
你很精明
you've been pretty smart.
比监管者更精
Smarter than the regulators, anyway.
告诉你谁才聪明 沃尔特
Tell you what's smart. Vaulter.
wise=投资者 apple=纽约人
我不管华尔街的人怎么说
I don't care what the wise apples say.
我还有点事
Well, uh, I've got a thing.
杰西 能送弗尼斯先生下去吗
Hey, Jess, will you take Mr. Furness down?
瞧瞧你 身处雷暴中心...
Look at you. Right in the eye of the raging storm and...
却淡然自若
and cool as a cucumber.
挺住 保持联系
Stay strong. Stay in touch.
怎么了
What happened?
他说我要没他就要溺死了
He said I was dead in the water without him
还想给我点甜头[撸管]
and tried to finger-bang me.
你怎么说
What'd you say?
我宁愿吃自己的屎
Said I'd rather eat my own shit.
-听说了吗  -什么
- Have you heard? - What?
股票跌破130美元了
Stock's gone below 130.
有时候你从派对上离开
You know sometimes you leave the party
会好奇大家都是怎么说你的
and you wonder what everyone's saying about you?
我的情况通常是"那个帅小伙[汉·索罗]是谁
With me it's usually "Who's that young Han Solo
怎样能让他来后入我啊"
and how do I get his dick in my ass?"
我知道他们怎么说我
Like, I know what they say about me.
怎么说
What?
这样 看见了吗
That. See that?
这就是人们有多不喜欢我
That's how much people don't like me.
他们也讨厌我 别把我落下
Hey, that's me too. Don't leave me out.
事实是
The truth is,
我们揭开他的虚张声势 虽然可能不是虚张声势
we call their bluff, which may not be a bluff,
这笔债被公开 我们就会失控
and the debt becomes public, and we lose control.
或者我们让股价回升 但又不行
Or we get the stock up, which we can't,
因为我们没法用魔法
because we can't "Magic" That,
或者我们还银行钱
or we pay the bank back,
但是 换那么多现金...
which, I mean, to realize that much cash...
股市会跌 太可怕了
stock sell-down, which is horrible.
没有好的办法
There is no good option.
-我能提个建议吗  -什么啊
- Can I suggest something? - Yeah?
我能建议咱们都把衬衫脱了吗
Can I suggest we all take our shirts off?
好吧 肯德尔你呢
OK. Kendall?
他们能写个破代码来管理这地方
They can write a fucking algorithm to run this place,
但这不是解决办法
but that's not the answer.
那不是我们
That's not us.
所以... 破罐破摔
So... break shit up.
就破坏掉
Like, just disrupt.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
脱掉衬衫 仅此而已
Takin' my shirt off. That's all.
肯 让他把衬衫穿上
Ken, make him put his shirt on.
我不... 我不...
I don't... uh, I don't...
-我他妈不知道怎么...  -脱啊
- I don't fuckin' know. I... - Shirt off.
脱啊
Shirt off.
脱
Shirts off.
外套也脱了啊你
How about your jacket off?
来吧 快点
Come on, man.
好吧 好吧
Yeah, all right. All right.
好
Good.
这样就好 来吧咱们
That's all. Let's go.
-好  -那...
- OK. - So...
最差情况是 我们卖掉股票 还能活
worst position, we sell down the stock, we survive.
我们可以从物质生产中裁掉一两个分支
Maybe we cut a title or two from physical production,
报纸方面 只是线上的
newspaper-wise. Online only.
这主意不错
I like that.
这是花两千万解决十个亿的问题
That is a $20 million solution to a billion dollar problem.
没错 但这个方向很正确
Yeah, but it's the right direction of travel.
我感觉挺对的
That feels right to me.
如果你想靠降价回本: 裁员
If you want stuff that works for the price: layoffs.
对 残酷 就是这样
Yum-yum. Blood! Yes!
看吧 脱衣办法
See? Shirts-off shit.
咱们能打个组合拳 裁员 卖钱
I guess it could be a package. Layoffs, sell-offs.
结构性撤回吗
Structured retreat?
对 但要有个理念
Well, yeah, but with a philosophy.
-好吧  -好
- OK. - Yeah.
-好吗  -好
- OK? I mean, - OK.
那我们只需要问问或者 告诉爸
I guess we just have to ask or, you know, tell Dad.
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
-终于 -来了
- Finally. - Hi.
宝贝儿 来
Hey, sweetie. Hi.
你好啊 猛男
What's up, slugger?
谢谢你来了
Thanks for joining us.
事实上 我不能待很久
Actually, I can't stay long.
很显然我们也是
Apparently goes for us, too.
玛西娅阿姨不许我们看爷爷
Aunt Marcia won't let us see Grandpa.
是吧 孩子们
Right, kids?
-你好 玛西娅  -肯德尔
- Hey, Marcia. - Kendall.
你好吗
How are you?
-好着呢  -好啊
- Good. - Good.
他怎么样 还好吗
How's he doing? Is he OK?
他在好转 好转得很快
He's improving. He's really improving.
-那就好  -是啊
- Great. - Yeah.
因为我大概该告诉他点事
'Cause I should probably let him know something.
他在休息
He's resting.
抱歉 现在不行
I'm sorry, it's not a good time.
好吧
Ok.
但是我助理打电话的时候...
Well, it's just when my assistant called...
她跟琼说的 不是我
She spoke with Joan, not me.
-明白了  -好
- Got it. - Yeah.
那你能告诉他 我来过了
Well, uh, let him know, will you, that I stopped by,
想跟他谈话 让他了解策略吗
wanted to talk to him, keep him abreast of moves?
你愿意的话 告诉我就行 我会转告
If you like, you can tell me, I'll pass it on.
麻烦你告诉他我们...
will you just tell him that we're...
我们要撤退 战术上讲
um, we're retreating, tactically.
这样听着不太对
Well, that doesn't sound right.
不是退出市场 但...
Not retreating, quite, but...
这很难解释
It's hard to explain.
我相信你在做对的事
I'm sure you're doing the right thing.
-好吧 谢了 回见  -再见
- OK, thanks. See you soon. - See you.
-那啥 斯图伊  -怎么了
- So, Stewy? - Mm-hmm?
你知道 大家都恨你吗
You know how, like, everyone hates you?
不 我不知道这事
Well, no, that's not something I'm aware of.
真的 他们恨你
Oh, sure. They do.
私募股权: 投资于非上市股权 或上市公司非公开交易股权
私募股权 禁锢你的双手
Private equity, getting your meat hooks in,
凿你的利益跟他妈吸血鬼蝗虫似的
chiseling your profit like a vampire locust fuck.
你在干嘛 开耍笑庆祝会吗
What is this? Is this a roast?
我他妈还有事要做呢
Because I have shit to do.
-我有个主意  -好
- I've had an idea. - OK.
你别占领我们了 你给我四十亿怎么样
How about instead of taking us over, you give me $4 billion?
我还当老板
I stay boss,
你别劫垃圾公司的破烂了
you stop raiding shitty companies for scraps,
你投资给一家蓝筹[靠谱]公司 仅一次
you invest, for once, in a blue-chip corporation,
一家现在被低估的
one that is currently, you know, undervalued
由于一些对它领导人无因的担心
because of some unfounded concerns about its leadership,
比如 小公子方特洛伊[电影]
I.E., Little Lord Fuckleroy here,
故事转折后... 皆大欢喜
the story twists... happy ending for all.
-好吧 要我说实话吗  -对
- OK. Full disclosure? - Yeah.
我酒还没醒 比平常都严重
I have a hangover. And it's bigger than normal.
要不咱们去做过去经常做的事
Why don't we do what we did back in the day,
咱们去厕所吧 来点儿小东西
let's go to the bathroom, have a little sumthin'-sumthin',
磕出点想法 把它们都想出来
just knock out a few ideas, just bash 'em out.
-不 我不行  -当然
- No. Not for me. - Of course.
当然 我了解
Yeah, yeah, of course.
你介意我去 来一小口吗
Do you mind if I have, like, just like a taste of it?
真的吗 兄弟
Really, dude?
好 好
Yeah. Mm-kay.
-你好了吗  -还没
- Are you done? - Uh, no.
显然 我一般不会
Obviously, I don't generally
在上市公司买少数股权
take a minority stake in a public company.
是啊 很明显 因为你是个寄生虫
Yeah, obviously, because you're a parasite.
来一次大的怎么样
How about for once you make things bigger?
和你老伙计一起
You know, with your old pal?
-你好了吗  -好了
- Are you done? - Yeah.
我甚至不能去想这个
Well, I can't even begin to think about this.
但如果我能...
But if I could...
要卖的话 我还需要投票股份
to sell it, I'm gonna need voting stock.
只要家族还掌权就行
As long as the family maintain control?
对 实权 我还要个董事会席位
Well, effective control. I'm also gonna need a board seat.
我会强加给你的 兄弟 为了好看
Oh, I'd force it on you, dude. For the optics.
丫的新总裁有他妈大把钱来投资
Shit hot new CEO has some hot shit new money for investment.
新一代
New generation.
我让欠债这事不上新闻
I keep the debt out of the news.
姐妹们他妈的自立自强
Fuckin' sisters doin' it for theyselves.
我并非完全反对这提议
I'm not necessarily totally opposed to this notion.
没错 幸好我完全懂你
That's right, and luckily I speak Stewy,
你这是在说 "我他妈好性奋准备大干一场了"
and that's Stewy for "I have a fuckin' raging hard-on for this."
格雷格 来吧 伙计
Greg. Come on, buddy.
参加第一次核心高管骨干会议
First meeting of the senior management cadre.
-好的  -没错 快来
- Uh-huh. - Yeah, come on.
好的 了不起 真好
Uh, great. Great stuff. Great.
那啥 我刚才在浏览员工邮件
You know, I was lookin' through employee emails,
顺便说下 这完全合法
which, by the way, is totally legal,
你告诉我 我口臭吗
and, uh, does my breath smell?
说实话
Honestly?
不 不臭 就是呼吸的味道
No, no. No, I mean, it smells of breath,
但...
but...
公园这部分业务太不稳定
You know, there's too much drift in Parks.
我要撼动那棵树
I'm gonna shake that tree.
我可能会把你当沙袋打 可以吧
I might punch-bag you a little, is that cool?
没问题 当成沙袋打... 行
Sure. As in, like, punch... Yeah.
早啊 大家
Morning, people.
开始吧
Kick-off.
提个问题
Here's a question.
我们齐聚于"主题公园部"
Here we are, out in the Theme Park Division,
但回答我
but tell me this:
专业来讲 如果你可以做任何事
if you could really do anything, professionally,
在任何地方工作 你想去哪做什么
and work anywhere, where would that be?
失陪
Excuse me.
不行 小西
Uh-huh. Oh, no. Shiv.
我正开第一次会呢
I'm in the middle of the first m-meeting.
好吧 很难...
Well, it's hard...
康纳飞过来了
Connor's flying in?
好吧 好吧
Ok. Ok.
好吧 拜拜 好的
All right, bye. Right.
操
Fuck!
-你查她的底了  -没错 没必要告诉肯
- You background checked her? - Yeah, no need to tell Ken.
合法吗
Is that legal?
你不必知道
You don't need to know.
谁都可以查别人吗
can anybody do that on anybody?
好吧 听着 她第一任丈夫 黎巴嫩商人
OK, so, first husband, Lebanese businessman.
-没错 我记得  -对
- Yeah, I remember. - Right.
他们在巴黎过得纸醉金迷 很多派对 很多政客参加
They had the high life in Paris, lot of parties, with pols,
还有很多作家 另外还有很多骗子和混球
and writers, and also a lot of shitbags and slimeballs
而且还有军火商 石油大亨
and arms dealers, oil guys.
-再往前呢  -好吧 再往前...
- And further back? - Well, further back...
就有些复杂
further back is complicated.
完全没线索
There's no leads.
-什么  -对
- What? - Yeah.
-这就...  -奇怪了 是的
- Is that... - Weird? Yes.
-这可不是好兆头 没错  -对
- Ominous, yes. - Yeah.
显然这有些古怪
It's apparently a little weird.
有两种可能
And there are two possibilities.
要么她是凭空蹦出来的
Either she came from kind of nowhere,
从的黎波里 到黎巴嫩
Tripoli, Lebanon,
三十一岁在巴黎发迹
turns up in Paris, age 31,
一个小小的出版社助理
a publishing assistant,
嫁给第一任丈夫
and then just marries this guy.
-都说得通  -或者
- Fine. - Or.
或者... 她把底洗净了
Or... cleanup job.
你好 玛西娅
Oh! Hey, Marcia.
布谷鸟模仿得不错
Great impression of a cuckoo.
打开门就看到你等着
Door opens, and there you are.
-你们好  -你好
- Hello, everybody. - Hi.
你好 这位是康纳
Yeah, hi. This is Connor,
洛根的长子 还记得吗
Logan's firstborn son, you remember him?
这是汤姆 我的伴侣 他俩摞一块快四米了
And this is Tom, my partner, and together
你绝对拦不住 请让我们见他
they're over 12 feet of We Would Like To See Him, Please.
你们这是想硬闯 对吗
Are you trying to force entry, is that it?
天呐 我以为我们就是顺路看看
Oh, boy. I thought we were just stopping by.
我通常避免冲突 大家都深呼吸吧
I usually try to avoid confrontation. Let's all breathe.
他纯粹只是不宜见人
He simply isn't up to visitors.
这是针对我签的那些文件吗 或是...
Is this about me signing some pieces of paper? Or...
请不要这样 小西
Oh, please, Shiv.
情况已经很艰难了
It's very difficult as it is.
你他妈眼泪攻势我吗
Oh, the fuckin' waterworks?
是吗 你要开始哭了 得了吧
Is that it? You're gonna cry now? Please.
西沃恩
Siobhan.
简直不敢相信你要拦着我去看我自个老爸
I can't believe you would try and stop me seeing my father.
而我不敢相信你要违背他的意愿
And I can't believe you will try against his wishes.
你好 爸爸
Hi. Dad.
你好
Hey.
你能先出去吗
Can you?
还好吧
Hey.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
不错吗
Yeah?
你看起来不错 你... 看起来好多了
You're looking good. You're... You look better.
汤姆和我要搬进来 我们在打算
So, hey, Tom and I are gonna move here, we think.
长期在这 在华盛顿少待一些
More permanently. Less time in D.C.
对了 我们订婚了
Oh, and we're engaged.
他想问你来着
Um, he wanted to ask you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我去找... 找琼 好吗
I'm gonna... go get Joan. OK?
没... 没关系
It's... It's fine.
我... 会再来
I... I'll be back.
-罗伊先生怎么样  -还行 他...
- How is Mr. Roy? - Yeah. He...
一切都好吗
Everything OK?
挺好的
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
他看起来好多了
He's looking better.
早晨这段时间通常不大合适
Morning isn't usually a good time.
你懂的 他打了吗啡 头脑不清
You know, the morphine, he gets confused.
他不想让你们看到他神志不清的样子
He doesn't like you all to see him when he's not himself.
没错 他确实不太对劲
Uh-huh. Yeah, he wasn't himself.
-没错  -那么...
- Right. - So...
小西 我很注重隐私
Shiv, I'm a private person.
不是所有人都含着金汤匙出生
Not all of us are born into good ease.
好
Ok.
所以如果你想知道关于我的事
So if you want to know anything about me,
来问我 我会告诉你的
just ask me, and I will tell you.
好的
Uh-huh.
西沃恩 老爸怎么样
Hey, Siobhan, how's Pop?
好 不错 他挺好的
Yeah. Yeah, no, he's good.
-好了 再见  -他累了
- OK, bye. - He's tired.
午安
Good afternoon.
波尔克先生 谢谢你腾出时间
Thanks for making time for us, Mr. Polk.
客气了
Not at all.
我们一直在研究我们能提供的条件
We've been looking at the terms we can offer,
我想你已经看过我们的方案了
I think you've seen what we've put together.
我看了 看了
I have. I have.
是个很残酷的方案
It's a very brutal structure.
是的 目前我们只能提供这些
Well, these are the terms we think we can offer right now.
我的意思是 你按这个方案盈的利
I mean, I don't know, the margin you're making,
甚至可以说你是在...
you might even say you were...
好吧 "敲诈"的话可能有点过了
well, I mean, "Extortion" Is an ugly word,
不过 你基本就是拿锯子直接把我阉了
but, you know, so is "Buzz saw castration."
听着 我们应该保持专业态度 不是吗
Look, I think we should keep things professional, don't you?
当然 当然了
Uh-huh. Sure. Sure.
专业态度来说 我们选择还钱
And professionally, we're going to repay.
-你是说...  -解决了
- As in...? - We're good.
一切都好极了 我们不需要你
Everything's golden. We don't need you.
一切都能继续蒙在鼓里 我们将另寻
This can all stay private, and I'll be looking elsewhere
银行合伙人 同时以超音速发展
for a banking partner as we go supersonic.
再见
Good-bye.
-罗伊先生...  -还有 操你丫的
- Mr. Roy... - And fuck you.
-你来过这吗  -没有
- Have you been here? - No.
这里好极了 我想点...
It's super-good. I'm thinking...
"兔子的全部"
"All of the rabbit."
-全部的  -我的问题是
- All of it. - Well, that's my question,
就是他们说"兔子的全部"时
is when they say "All of the rabbit,"
意思是 整只兔子吗
do they mean, like, all of the rabbit?
它不可能是整只兔子啊
I mean, it can't be, like, all of it.
所以我们是在庆祝斯图伊的钱吗
So, is this the Stewy money we're celebrating?
因为我看到了新闻
Because I saw the news.
好吧 我不会说我就是那个人
Well, I wouldn't say that I'm the man,
但如果有那么个人的话 假设
but if there were a man, hypothetically,
他跟我相似度是极高的
he might look a lot like me.
是啊 我用私募股权资金解决了债务问题
Yeah, I solved the debt issue with private equity money.
-我为你感到高兴  -是的...
- I'm very happy for you. - Yeah. Well...
...问题是 所有这些
...the thing is, all of that,
让我思考了很多事
it's made me think about everything,
就是... 你知道
and, um...well, you know,
这是我的结论
like, here's where I'm at.
我爱你
I love you.
好吧
Ok.
好吧 谢谢你 知道了
Well, thank you. Noted.
-就这样吗 得了  -这...
- That's it? Come on. - That's...
-"我... 也..."  -肯
- "And... I..." - Uh, Ken.
好吧 我不确定自己爱不爱你
OK. Uh, I'm not sure that I love you.
是的 你爱的
Yeah, you do.
去你的
Fuck you.
听着 你想我们分居 是吗
Look, you want us to live separately, right?
我们现在还不知道原因 是你说的
We don't know why right now, you say you do.
这件事让我不高兴了
Now, that makes me unhappy.
另一方面 你声称
On the other hand, you claim,
当然我是不信你的
and of course I don't believe you,
我们在一起会令你不幸福
that us being together will make you unhappy.
所以我们俩中总有一个不幸福
So one of us is going to be unhappy.
我不明白为什么那个人必须是我
I just don't see why it has to be me.
厉害 我辩不过这个逻辑
Wow. I-I cannot argue with that logic.
不 它就是不成立的逻辑
No, it's, like, impenetrable logic.
就像在跟一个精神病争吵
It's the argument of a psychopath.
假设 这位精神病可能是一个男人
A psychopath who might, hypothetically, be the man.
爱你的男人
Who loves you.
去你的
Fuck you.
我们不能分手
We are not breaking up.
不 我们必须分手
Yes. We are. I--
-我们不能分手  -必须分手
- We are not breaking up. - Yes, we are.
抱歉
Sorry.
-我们不能 不能  -不 我们必须分
- We are not. Not. - Yes, we are.
-不能  -分 必须分
- No! - Yes! Yes!
-我们不能分手  -我们他妈的必须分
- We are not breaking up. - We fucking are.
早上好
Good mornin'.
你想下来锻炼吗
So, did you want to work out down here?
想让我把车开到公园 然后跑酷吗
Want me to take my car to the park, we can parkour it?
问题是这样的 布雷克斯
Well, here's the thing, Brex.
我啥运动都没法做了
I can't do shit, really,
因为从周一起 我的背就一直受累
because my back has been fucked since Monday.
怎么受累
Fucked how?
我猜你投保了吧
Well, I assume you're insured?
我每一天都在这里 瞎搞一气
I mean, I do big, big shit here, every day,
因此失去了四分之一的运营能力
so losing even a quarter of a percent of my operating capacity,
也就是百万美元受到影响
that has million dollar implications.
所以我想 也许一个测试案例
So I'm thinkin' maybe a test case,
我扔给你三四打穿白鞋的律师
I throw three or four dozen white-shoe lawyers at you
看看真的从肉体上
and see what it would be
摧毁一个人会是什么样
like to actually physically destroy someone.
伙计 我不知道发生了什么
Dude, I don't know what happened,
但我保证能力挽狂澜
but I'm sure I can fix it.
他妈逗你呢
Fuck you.
去你丫的 兄弟
Oh, fuck you, dude!
天啊 看看你 看你那张脸
Jeez, look at you. Look at your face!
你真是一坨屎
You're a piece of shit.
是的
Yeah.
但也不是 我想说
But, uh, no, I'm just sayin'
你需要更加严肃地对待这件事
you need to take this more seriously.
好吧
Ok.
好的
我得走了
I have to go.
马来娅在哪 她不能...
What about Malaya, can't she...?
不行 艾弗森会吓坏的
No. Iverson will freak out.
-那啥 拉瓦  -干嘛
- Hey, Rava. - What?
要不咱们不做不休吧
Why don't we just do it all?
你懂吗 复合
You know? Back together?
... 咱们日后再聊
... let's talk later?
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
喂
Hey.
昨晚很好 对吧
That was nice, right?
-就那么回事  -什么
- Nevertheless. - What?
听着 我...
Look, I, um...
我不知道 我不知道
I-- I don't know. I don't know.
也许是...
Maybe it's, um...
靠 这就像... 你已经翻篇了
Shit. It's like... It's like you're moving on,
让我觉得翻篇也是可以的
and maybe that makes me feel OK about moving on too.
不是的 我没有翻篇 拉瓦
No. I'm not moving on. Rava.
瞎说
That's bullshit.
我认识了个律师
I got a lawyer.
他人很好
He's nice.
我们就这样很好地保持下去 可以吗
Let's just keep this all really, really nice, OK?
玛西娅 一切都还好吗
Marcia? Everything all right?
肯德尔 你父亲想见你
Kendall, you father would like to see you.
...十几名士兵从空中涌入制毒厂
...A dozen troops swarmed the drugs farm from the air,
从直升机上降落 而另一队步行进入
descending from helicopters, while another unit entered on foot.
它声称贩毒集团
It's claimed the drug trafficking ring
已经存在超过三年...
had been in existence for over three years...
看看你
Hey. Look at you.
能坐起来了
Sitting up.
还他妈能看新闻了
Fuckin' watchin' the news.
很高兴见到你 爸
It's good to see you, Dad.
好吧...
Well...
你知道吗 你倒下后股市一泻千里
you understand after you went down, the stock tanked.
可能你该感到受宠若惊
I mean, you should be flattered, I guess.
我们的选择都很糟糕
We had some pretty shitty options.
因为你在那笔贷款上赌了一把
I mean, you took a gamble on that loan.
但我找到了用私募股权来解决的办法
But I found us a private equity solution.
所以...
So...
我想过要咨询你 但...
I tried consulting you, but...
人们喜欢现在的情况
People like the shape of this.
卡洛丽娜说分析师的议论很乐观
Karolina says there's positive analyst noise.
我们目前占有36%
We are at 36%,
加上有效控制权
with effective control,
再加上用专用款项做一些动作
plus a war chest to make some moves.
我们... 我们的状态不错 爸
We're... We're in good shape, Dad.
你只管养好身体就行
You just keep getting better.
我能行的
I got this.
蠢 豁
Fugin idiot.
爸
Dad?
你需要点什么吗
Hey, can I get you something?
你...
You...
是...
are...
他...
fuh...
...他妈的蠢货
...fucking idiot.
你好
Hi.
我想...
I think, uh...
THE SUB-MAN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠